Stamfield had had a bit of a go at the girl over her timekeeping.
Stamfield批评过她不守时的问题
But otherwise, all was hunky-dory.
不过别的都没问题
So, have a wonderful night with your family and friends.
祝你与家人朋友度过一个愉快的夜晚
And I hope to see you soon.
希望很快和你见面
And she'll be seeing you sooner than you both thought.
你们俩都想不到这么快就能见面了
You last saw her eight years ago
你上次见她还是八年前
when you were her husband's best man.
那时候你给她丈夫做伴郎
But she's here tonight. Sarah Coyle then.
今晚她来到了现场 以前是Sarah Coyle
Now, Sarah Sellars!
现在是Sarah Sellars
Yes, as Sarah said,
对 正如Sarah所说
you were never that keen on school work.
你们一直都不怎么努力学习
And as our next witness will testify,
我们下一位证人将会证明
your eagerness to play football often got you into trouble.
你对踢足球的热爱经常让你惹一身麻烦
It was only a kick-about after school.
只是放学后随便踢踢
But when he got home, Jack was really in hot water.
但是Jack回家之后 就有麻烦了
Yes, you've not seen him for a while, your school pal
对 你有段时间没见过他了 你的同学
and fellow footballing hopeful from Londonderry,
来自伦敦德里的爱踢足球的朋友
you were best man at his wedding, George Sellars!
你曾是他婚礼上的伴郎 George Sellars
So, tell us, George, what sort of trouble did Jack used to get in?
George 跟我们说说 Jack都是惹上什么麻烦
Well, down the rec, we didn't have a proper goal,
我们踢球那里根本就没有正式的球门
so we'd use our jumpers to mark the posts, like.
我们就用衣服来标记球门柱子
This one game, he gets his jumper absolutely wrecked.
有一次踢球 他把自己的衣服弄得破破烂烂
He knew he'd catch it off his mam, so he borrowed mine.
他知道肯定会被妈妈骂 就借了我的衣服
-Did the deception work, Mrs Swift?  -No, Eamonn, it didn't!
-骗过您了吗 Swift太太  -没有 Eamonn 根本没有
It wasn't Jackie's name tag that was sewn into the collar of his sweater,
衣服领子上缝的不是Jackie的姓名牌
it was George's, so I knew they'd been out and up to no good.
而是George的 所以我就知道了他们在外面没干好事
I said to him, "You'll get a clatter off your daddy when he gets home!"
我跟他说 等你爸回来看他怎么唠叨你吧
Rest his soul.
愿他安息
Thank you, George Sellars!
谢谢你 George Sellars
And before long, your name reached the ears
没过多久 你的名字就传到了
of someone who was to change the course of your life.
那个即将改变你命运的人耳朵里
A docker friend of your late father who, in his spare time,
你已故父亲的一位朋友 平时是码头工人
acted as part-time coach and talent scout
业余兼职足球教练和球探
for football clubs here in England.
为英国的足球俱乐部物色人才
-Duke Ward.  -Yes.
-Duke Ward  -对
That's right, it's the man who spotted all that young potential,
没错 就是那位发掘了年轻新星的
a legendary football scout in Northern Ireland, Marmaduke Ward!
北爱尔兰传奇球探 Marmaduke Ward
Good to see you, Jackie.
见到你真好 Jackie
Duke, tell me, what was your reaction when you first saw Jack?
Duke 你第一次见到Jack是什么反应
Well, Eamonn, to tell you the truth, it was terrible.
Eamonn 说老实话 还挺糟糕的
Five feet, four, and less meat on him than a whippet.
一米六出头 瘦得皮包骨头
But I knew, the moment I saw this fella,
但是 我看到他的第一眼就知道
that he could be something very, very special
只要他努力练习
if he put the hard work in
再加上有人管理他
and had somebody to take him in hand.
他将来会成就非凡
We got him up to the mark,
我们帮他达到了标准
and then I had no hesitation
然后毫不犹豫地
in recommending him to the Wanderers.
把他推荐给流浪者队
And I think you'll agree, he hasn't done too bad so far.
你肯定也同意 到现在为止他踢得还不错
Indeed, he hasn't.
确实 很不错
Thank you, Duke Ward.
谢谢 Duke Ward
Now, to close tonight, we have someone else
今晚的压轴戏 还有个人
who's here to pay tribute to you.
要来向你致敬
A young man to whom you were a schoolboy hero,
对这位年轻人来说 你是他的儿时偶像
and who may himself be facing the kind of adulation
你已经习以为常的那些赞誉
you've gotten used to.
也许也正等着他
That's right, Eamonn. But there's only one Jack Swift.
没错 Eamonn 但只有一个Jack Swift
Yes, that's right. It's the young striker
没错 就是这位年轻的前锋
who's being hailed as "the next Jack Swift".
被誉为下一个Jack Swift
Cowley Town centre-forward
Cowley镇中锋
and Northern Ireland international, John-Paul Martinelli!
北爱尔兰国际比赛选手 John-Paul Martinelli
I saw him this morning and he never let on.
我今早见过他 他一个字也没透露
So, John-Paul, what is it you'd like to say to Jack?
那么 John-Paul 你想对Jack说些什么
Jack, you've been a hero, not just to me,
Jack 你一直是个英雄 不只是对我来说
but to thousands of other schoolboys.
还有成千上万个男孩子
And I know everyone back home
我们北爱的每个人
and here in the UK is just so proud of you,
还有英国人都特别为你感到骄傲
and what you've achieved in your career.
为你职业生涯的成就感到骄傲
Well, hopefully, it's not over yet!
希望我不会止步于此
Indeed not.
那当然
But for now, at least, Jack Swift, this is your life.
但是现在为止呢 Jack Swift 这就是你的生活
My playing days are mostly behind me.
我踢球都是以前的事了
Oh, look, here he is. It's Duke.
他来了 这位是Duke
The unluckiest man in showbusiness.
娱乐业最不幸的人
Now, what was it you made for discovering Jack?
发掘了Jack给你带来了多少收入
15 quid finder's fee, wasn't it?
15镑中介费 对吧
On top of the £2.10 a week retainer, of course. No.
当然还有每周2镑底薪 算了
No, you should come and work for me.
你还是来给我打工吧
Well, for some of us, it's not about the money.
对于有些人来说 这不光是钱的问题
But then, I wouldn't expect a man like you
不过我知道 像你这种人
to know anything about that.
也不明白这个道理
-What man like me?  -A parasite.
-我这种人  -寄生虫
Where were you on the freezing, cold winter mornings
我带着他在天寒地冻的冬天早晨训练的时候
I had him out training?
你在哪呢
Nowhere. That's where you were.
你还不知道在哪呢
And yet, you've bled Jack near enough dry.
而且 你快把Jack的血吸干了
And now you've got your claws into John-Paul.
现在又把爪子伸向了John-Paul
So, you're all set to ruin him, too.
所以你打算把他也给毁了
You're a grasper.
你就是个吸附者
You make me sick to my stomach.
真让我恶心够够的
All that stamina.
这么有耐性啊
I think that when you come and play for the Wanderers
如果你来为流浪者队效力
that we're going to be very good friends.
我们会成为很好的朋友
Oh, it's you.
啊 是你啊
Be a darling and go and fetch me a little drinkie.
帮个忙去给我拿杯饮料吧
I'm a detective sergeant at Thames Valley, Mrs Fenner.
我是泰晤士谷警察局的一名探长 Fenner太太
I'm not a wine waiter.
不是服务员
I'm sure your husband can freshen your glass.
你丈夫应该可以帮你把酒杯加满
Er, vodka martini, wasn't it, Mrs Fenner?
是伏特加马提尼吧 Fenner太太
Cecily. Please.
叫我Cecily吧
No mistaking you for Cupid, is there?
-Sweetheart...  -You might have mentioned this.
-亲爱的  -你可以跟我说一声的
Oh, well, we were all sworn to secrecy, weren't we?
我们都发誓要保密了 对吧
But you knew it was gonna happen
但是你知道这件事
and you knew there was a threat against his life.
也知道他面临生命威胁
Er, what can I say? I don't know what this
我能说什么呢 这个生命威胁的事
threat business is about any more than you do.
我知道的也不比你多
I'm grateful you're looking out for him.
谢谢你在
But by this time tomorrow, it'll all be over.
不过等明天这个时候 就全都结束了
Well, no, the threat was if he played.
不是 威胁是说如果他踢比赛的话
He hasn't played yet.
他还没踢呢
Mr Lofthouse...
Lofthouse先生
The Doncaster Dynamo.
I saw you play against Millwall in, er, '54, was it? A cup tie.
我看过你踢的那场对阵米尔沃尔队的比赛 54年对吧 杯赛淘汰赛
I used to take my boy Sam there when he was smaller.
Before we moved to Oxford,
of course.
Come on, let's split.
But what about your family?
It's...
It's your party.
They're not here for me.
Right, OK.
Hey, Jack, can I get you a drink?
Not right at the minute, Georgie.
Are you sure?
Cos I know Sarah'd love to catch up.
She must've just nipped out
to powder her nose.
She'll be back in a minute,
I'm sure.
I can't have a late night, George.
I've got a match tomorrow.
Are you staying on for it?
Yeah, of course.
We're all put up at the Plaza.
Your mum and sisters and everyone.
Great.
Great, we'll do something after,
then. OK?
Home!
You're late, Dad!
Work went on.
You missed Sam on the telephone.
I gave him your best.
All right over there, is it...
..with the locals?
Behaving themselves?
He didn't say.
I asked if he was looking
after himself. He said he was.
I'll put the kettle on.
Nothing for me this late.
Fair dos. Here...
you'll never guess
who I met tonight.
Who? Someone we know?
Eamonn Andrews.
Eamonn Andrews?
Fancy!
What's he like?
Very nice.
But not as tall as he looks
on the telly.
Sorry to drag you away.
I just had to get out.
You know, get away.
Sometimes, it takes me like that.
I get tired of it.
Of what?
Being Jack Swift.
What, the adulation, women, money?
My commiserations!
Aye.
It looks great from the outside.
But everyone wants something.
A signed photo.
A cut of your wages.
To be your friend.
To take them to bed so they can run
to the papers about it.
And what do you want?
The love of a good woman.
I had one, too.
And I let her go.
It was put to me I had to choose.
It was her...
..or success at the football.
There's not a day goes by...
HE CHUCKLES
And now they want to kill me for it.
Have you got a girl?
Er, no. No, not at the moment.
I could get some company over.
Make a call.